Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Hispania Records, 1980-1985 and undated RL.11007
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Hispania records
1980-1985 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Hispania
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11007
3 Linear Feet
Division of the J. Walter Thompson Company, specializing in marketing communications and advertising to the North American Hispanic market. Founded in 1980, its clients and operations were folded into Mendoza Dillon & Associates upon WPP's acquisition of that agency in 1988. Collection spans the years 1980-1985 and includes correspondence, marketing research, advertising strategy reports and other items. Companies represented include Bumble Bee, Burger King, Ford, Kraft, Sears, Ward Candy (Chunky bar) and William Underwood. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Collection Overview
Collection spans the years 1980-1985 and includes correspondence, marketing research, advertising strategy reports and other items. Companies represented include Bumble Bee, Burger King, Ford, Kraft, Sears, Ward Candy (Chunky bar) and William Underwood. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Hispania Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Douglass L. Alligood Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office Records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office. Goldfarb Consultants Ford Research Reports
Warwick Baker O'Neill Records
Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Demographic surveys; Demographic surveys -- United States; Marketing research; Hispanic American consumers; Marketing research -- United States; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- United States; J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company. Hispania; Burger King Corporation; Ford Motor Company; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Bumble Bee Seafoods, Inc; Kraft Foods Company; William Underwood Company
- Memoranda, 1981; 1
  - Memos to Fermina Platon, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Memos to Gerri Polcari, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Memos to J. Walter Thompson, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Memos to Jack Aquirre, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Memos to Kathy Nicolini, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Memos to Nancy Tellet, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Memos to Raoul Gonzalez, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Memos to Tony Ruiz, 1981 (Box 1)
- Alphabetical Files, 1980-1985 and undated; 2
  - Brouillard communications, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Bumble Bee, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Burger King, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Caballero radio, 1981 (Box 1)
  - California Milk advisory Board, 1981; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Day Cruise Line, 1981 (Box 1)
  - De Armas Publications, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Ford 1st QTR Buy Sheets, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Ford 2nd QTR traffic lists, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Ford 4th QTR schedule summaries, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Ford Motor Company, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Ford Print Activity--Lincoln Mercury, 1985 (Box 2)
  - General media, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Hispania Media Department Presentation, 1980-1985; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - internal media procedures, 1981 (Box 2)
  - JWT Media Research Dept, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Kraft Advertising & Promotion Scheduels, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Kraft Advertising Expenditures, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Kraft billing, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Kraft billing, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Kraft Broadcast Schedule 1st qtr, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Kraft budget control sheets, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Kraft Calle Ocho, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Kraft Chicagofest, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Kraft Conference Reports, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Kraft Coupon Program, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Kraft Desfile de la Hispanidad, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Kraft Estimate Openers, 1981; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Kraft Estimate Openers, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Kraft estimate openers 4th Qtr, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Fortunata & Jacinta, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Hispanic Media Advertising Program (Media Recommendation), 1981 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Historical Media Overview, Media Recommendation, Misc., 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kraft LULAC (magazine), 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Make Goods, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Media Estimates, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Media Information, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Media Rate Analysis, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Merchandising, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Misc. Financial (Billing, Budget, Estimates, Etc.), 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Misc. Hispanic Events, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Monterey Jack "Mini" Plan, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Multi- Products, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Orange Juice 4th QTR Media Plan, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Outdoor, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Point of Sale, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Kraft radio buy sheets 3rd Qtr, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Kraft Radio Contracts, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Kraft Radio Schedules and Misc., 1981 (Box 5)
  - Kraft Reader's Digest, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Kraft SIN 1981 Rates (Box 5)
  - Kraft Spanish advertising, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Kraft Television, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Kraft TV Productions, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Lotus Reps, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Market data, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Marketron, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Misc. Radio representatives, 1981 (Box 5)
  - National Hardware Sale Estimates and Specs, 1985 (Box 5)
  - National Hardware Sale General, 1985 (Box 5)
  - National Hardware Sale Paperwork, 1985 (Box 5)
  - New Business, 1981 (Box 5)
  - P/W Radio, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Print Advertising, undated (Box 5)
  - Questions for Arbitron, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Richard Asch (Outdoor), 1980-1981 (Box 5)
  - Scrabble, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Sears, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Sears Big, Bright and White Sale General, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Selcom Inc, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Selecciones Reader's digest, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Shelly's Expense Vouchers, 1981 (Box 5)
  - SIN- Spanish Intl Network, 1981; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - special events and holidays, 1981 (Box 6)
  - WADO, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Ward Candy Co. (Chunky), 1981; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Warner - Lambert Media, 1981; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - William Underwood - Media Plan, Broken Letters, 1981 (Box 7)
  - William Underwood - Memos (general), billing, recipes, 1981 (Box 7)
  - William Underwood - Misc. Financial, Estimate Recaps, Budget/ Flowchart, 1981 (Box 7)
  - William Underwood - Sas-on contest, General correspondance, 1981 (Box 7)
  - WNJU-47, 1981 (Box 7)
  - World Wide Agencies (JWT), 1981 (Box 7)
  - Yankelovich study, 1981 (Box 7)